Vincent...
You complete my fate
The world unwinds inside of me
The halo crawls away
You refill my place
Come and save me
Believe in me and drink the wine and take my hand and fill me up
Golo presents
Come and save me
Re-l Mayer.
Kristeva.
Where is Vincent?
He didn't kill me.
So not all of his personality as Vincent has been lost.
However...
Does Vincent Law also intend to kill the Bureau Chief?
Where are you going?
I am his Entourage.
My duty is to protect and guide him.
I see.
meditation  shackles
Where are you, Papa?
Grandfather,
Romdeau is finished.
I...
always hated this city.
A world full of lies.
But this is truth.
If so, then what I've been seeking is too...
You are...
Nice to meet you, my other self.
Who are you?
I?
I am Re-l Mayer.
I am Re-l Mayer!
Not you.
Stop!
Don't do such sad things.
You are the one who helped Vincent remember me...
remember Monad.
What are you talking about?
What's this "Monad"?
What's that got to do with me?
And why do you know Vincent?
He does not have to suffer any longer.
I want to save him.
Save him from the Creator's suffering.
The Creator's suffering?
He is the one who created Romdeau.
Don't tell her things she doesn't need to know.
Re-l,
I've been looking for you.
Daedalus.
So the Administrator did die.
No wonder I was allowed to enter.
Vincent created this city?
Yes.
Ask them.
Now that the Administrator is dead,
those stone statues have no further reason to keep their silence.
Who is she?
I told you not to wander around.
Daedalus, I want to see Vincent.
What?
I want to see Vincent.
You too?
Re-l!
Re-l, go back to the lab.
Cut the crap!
Vincent killed Grandfather.
Is that who he really is?
Then what should I do?
If he ceases to be himself, I...
And yet, Daedalus, even you...
I don't know!
He killed the Administrator, didn't he?
Then kill Vincent!
Vincent, Vincent...
It's always about him!
Oh, right...
I have to find my Re-l.
Daedalus...
I want my Re-l to see only me.
Please tell me what truths you know.
Re-l.
The truth...
would mean Romdeau's demise.
Did Vincent... Did Ergo PROXY return to this city to witness that?
We cannot discern what is in the Creator's mind.
Did Vincent really create this city?
This dome...
and several dozen beings on which the citizens were based.
The rest came from Womb System
maintenance and increased production...
Correct.
I have seen many domes in the outside world.
So those domes were also created by individual PROXIES...
PROXIES are gods.
And Romdeau is a utopia abandoned by God.
Abandoned?
Ergo left.
Along with a deep disappointment in himself.
Donov Mayer was entrusted.
Grandfather was... by Ergo?
Why did a PROXY, said to be omnipotent, abandon the city?
Why is this world rife with chaos?
It means PROXIES are not omnipotent.
To Romdeau, Ergo is indeed God.
An imperfect god, however.
That which is created by such a god is also imperfect.
And God abandoned us...
left us to live.
Then why did Romdeau invade Mosk?
Melancholy stemming from loss of glory and grandeur.
The ultimate revenge.
But Monad took our sight and shut
us tightly away with her closed eyes.
So our eyes no longer shine upon the land.
Do you understand?
What irony.
The Creator had returned unbeknownst to us.
An imperfect god...
We are...
It can't be...
The Creator's suffering...
Please don't suffer anymore.
Come to me, Vincent.
I will free you from the prison of suffering.
Re-l Mayer!
It can't be.
Here you go.
I did what you asked, didn't I?
Yes.
Daedalus Yumeno...
You're still alive?
You're surprisingly tough.
Where are the FP bullets?
Give me all of them.
Sure.
Take as many as you'd like.
Where did you hide them?!
No idea.
I forgot.
Oh, I remember now. I threw them away.
You bastard!
Why?!
Because we don't need them anymore.
I have to kill him... kill Vincent Law.
All I care about is having Re-l.
You intend to turn your back on reality
and wait for death with Re-l Mayer's replacement?
"Model citizens should throw things away."
I don't need you anymore either.
What?
You'll only be pathetic if you live any longer, Chief Raul.
It won't be beautiful.
I will not succumb.
I will fight to the very end!
As you wish.
Shoot 'im!
"Vincent" is a personality he created so he could forget
that he is a PROXY.
You said you wouldn't shoot for now.
So, I'm returning it to you.
Let's go together, Miss Re-l.
That an immigrant like me...
No, that's not it.
That a monster like me...
Vincent.
Did Romdeau continue to reject you, its Creator,
because you subconsciously wished it to be so?
Because you had made it so?
If everything was a setup, when you appeared before me
was Romdeau supposed to collapse?
Was it to make me kill you?
Was that why I was created?
And why you appeared...
and why I was helplessly drawn to you.
But why me?
This is true for you too...
No one...
No one can choose whom they will be when they're born.
No matter what manner of being they are...
Isn't that right, Vincent?
But now...
I feel as though my heart might shatter.
The ones who supported my existence disappear one by one.
Re-l.
This may be the truth for Romdeau,
but it is not the truth you should arrive at.
The truth I should arrive at?
That truth should not be something told to you by another,
but should come from within.
It does not matter who tells you the truth,
it is you who must discover the truth for yourself.
So there is a different truth for each of us?
Re-l, we have nothing more to say to you.
As long as evil and shame continue to exist...
Silence is our only joy.
Do not awaken us...
Until the end...
Leave us in peace...
Papa?
My truth...
Something bore down on me... something other than terror.
Every time I faced you, it became larger.
But that was...
It tickles.
You protected me, didn't you.
Because that man said he'd kill him.
Hey, Papa.
Pino has lots of feelings.
I'm happy sometimes and sad sometimes...
Lots of feelings!
I'm going far, far away.
But after leaving you,
I realized what it's like to miss you, Papa.
You have a lot of feelings too, don't you?
Can I... still see her?
Papa...
Would you miss me too, Papa?
Donov Mayer...
Vincent...
No, Ergo PROXY...
Have you regained your memories?
Yes.
I created this city.
I entrusted all of it to this man.
Why did you come back?
You knew I would turn the gun on you.
That's why.
You're going to kill me, aren't you?
You believe I'll pull the trigger?
If you wish it.
Why?
Don't think I'll do what you want.
I will not be manipulated by you.
That is my truth... the one I finally arrived at.
The message left for me in Mosk.
The two necklaces...
That which has been separated.
You have shown yourself to us many times.
You're listening, aren't you?
Vincent Law and Ergo PROXY...
Having lost his memories and possessing two personalities...
Vincent was the perfect disguise for you.
But my truth has revealed your existence,
the other shadow manipulating Vincent and Ergo PROXY.
Show yourself!
You're still nearby, aren't you?
Impressive, Re-l124C41.
It is your turn to find the truth.
So you have finally arrived, Vincent Law.
But can you escape... from this labyrinth?
Please
could
you
stop
the
noise,
I'm
trying
to
get
some
rest
Please
could
you
stop
the
noise,
I'm
trying
to
get
some
rest
From
all
the
un
born
chic
head
From
all
the
un
born
chic
head
What's
that...?
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
What's
that...?
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
My voice no longer reaches him.
But...
an awakened heart trembles beneath the blue skies.
meditation  proxy